Narrator: Part 3
Presenter: William didn’t have any money to buy a dynamo,
but he still continued to work on his prototype windmill with his friends Geoffrey and Gilbert.
He found a motor from an old cassette player which he fitted to his bamboo pole with plastic blades.
Then he connected the whole contraption with wires to a radio belonging to Geoffrey.
William	…‘What do we do now?’ Geoffrey asked.
‘Now, we wait for the wind.’ Then, the wind began to blow.
My blades started to spin and the wheel began to turn.
The radio began to pop and whistle, and suddenly there was music!
‘You hear that, man?’ I screamed. ‘We did it!’
I started planning for an even bigger windmill.
In a local scrapyard, I found…tractor rims half the size of my body,…pipes and ploughs.
The stripped chassis of several cars lay bleached by the sun… .
Over the next few weeks, my scrap pieces kept revealing themselves like a magic puzzle.
But still I had no generator. My family had no money.
Every time I’d see a dynamo on someone’s bike – usually broken – I’d think, what a waste.
I woke up each morning and looked at the pile of metal in the corner of my room,
then went to help my father clear the fields.
…Then one day, my friend Gilbert and I spotted a man with a dynamo on his bike.
I bent down and gave the pedal a spin. The headlamp – an old car bulb – flickered on. ‘It’s perfect.’
Gilbert turned to the guy. ‘How much to buy the dynamo?’ he said.
The guy refused at first, but no one was fool enough to refuse money at this time.
‘Two hundred kwacha,’ he said, ‘with the bulb.’
Gilbert’s father had given away all their food during the famine,
and he wasn’t farming as much because of his health. I was sure their money was low.
Still, Gilbert…reached into his pocket and pulled out 200 more kwacha
– two red paper notes – and handed them over.
The next day I began putting everything together.
I took the fan, blades, bolts and the dynamo outside behind our kitchen
and arranged them in a neat row along the hard, barren dirt.
The process of heating, melting, and reheating took nearly three hours.
…Once assembled, the wingspan of the blade system was more than 8 ft across. …
Now the challenge was to attach the bike to the blades.
…My plan was to build a tall wooden tower and put the machine on top of it.
For two days, the windmill remained hidden behind the house.
In the meantime, Geoffrey, Gilbert, and I set out to build my tower.